<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>offtropic on Leonardo Faria</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/categories/offtropic/</link><description>Recent content in offtropic on Leonardo Faria</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 11:41:56 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leonardofaria.net/categories/offtropic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Terminal tips tweets</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2020/01/20/terminal-tips-tweets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 11:41:56 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2020/01/20/terminal-tips-tweets/</guid><description>A while ago I started a thread on Twitter with a few terminal tips. There are lots of CLIs in NPM and they can be very handy in our daily work. Here they are and if you like them, follow me :)
1. list-scripts and npm-list-scripts give you a list of available npm script including what each script does. Useful for documentation:
💻 npm i -g list-scripts npm-list-scripts
🌎 https://t.co/QvvFEpEMeQ https://t.</description></item><item><title>Exploring device detection for better user experiences in 2020</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2020/01/15/exploring-device-detection-for-better-user-experiences-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 02:16:54 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2020/01/15/exploring-device-detection-for-better-user-experiences-in-2020/</guid><description>A few months ago I watched a great talk in Chrome Dev Summit about performance in slow devices.
It blew my mind all the work done by Facebook in identifying devices to create a better user experience. Fast-forward to now, I decided to study a bit more the topic and see what I could do at Thinkific.
User agents User agents are well-known by developers. We use them to detect bots, redirect users to a specific version of our website or append CSS classes on our page so we can create different experiences.</description></item><item><title>A simple Sinatra Auth</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/11/04/a-simple-sinatra-auth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 01:40:07 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/11/04/a-simple-sinatra-auth/</guid><description>Imagine you want to protect the content of a website created with Next.js, Hugo or your favourite static site generator. Github doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer this feature or Netlify offers authentication only in their paid plans. Decided to create something simple with Sinatra, TailwindCSS and ready to go in Heroku.</description></item><item><title>Creating a website for my Apple Collection</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/10/17/creating-a-website-for-my-apple-collection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:36:30 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/10/17/creating-a-website-for-my-apple-collection/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/collection.jpg" alt="Part of the collection">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A while ago I started an Apple Collection. After a few laptops and a few iDevices, I decided that I should start collecting info about my iThings. In the beginning, I created a gist containing model, serial number, how did I get the device, minimum/maximum OS, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The list kept going bigger and bigger and the content started looking messy. The natural way to organize my data would be inside a SQL database, with the information distributed in columns. After organizing the information in tables, I would create a graphQL API (the one cool kids use these days) to give me the data needed to populate my UI – probably written in React, compiled with Babel and packed with webpack.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Forcing the usage of yarn (and at a specific version)</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/10/11/forcing-the-usage-of-yarn-and-at-a-specific-version/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:40:46 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/10/11/forcing-the-usage-of-yarn-and-at-a-specific-version/</guid><description>&lt;p>People and organizations often have preferences for a specific package manager. At work, we decided to use Yarn due to emoji support (jk) but how to keep everybody using Yarn? &lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can use the &lt;a href="https://docs.npmjs.com/misc/scripts">preinstall hook&lt;/a> to check if the user run &lt;code>npm install&lt;/code>or &lt;code>yarn install&lt;/code>. Here is one example:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-js" data-lang="js">&lt;span style="color:#d14">&amp;#34;scripts&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span> {
&lt;span style="color:#d14">&amp;#34;preinstall&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#d14">&amp;#34;node -e \&amp;#34;if(process.env.npm_execpath.indexOf(&amp;#39;yarn&amp;#39;) === -1) throw new Error(&amp;#39;You must use Yarn to install, not NPM&amp;#39;)\&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span>,
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Disabling autofill in Chrome</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/10/02/disabling-autofill-in-chrome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 16:58:52 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/10/02/disabling-autofill-in-chrome/</guid><description>&lt;p>Autofill in form elements is a very useful feature in browsers. Creating new accounts or shopping in an online store are examples of this feature saving us time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, the autofill feature can be a problem for SaaS products. Imagine that you want to edit the email address of one of your users. You hit edit in one screen and once you get a form with your user data Chrome will replace their email to your email. This is not a good user experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MDN has an article showing “How to turn off form autocompletion”. The solution is using the autocomplete attribute with an off value. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in Chrome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Digging in Stackoverflow and Google results, I found a &lt;a href="https://bugs.chromium.org/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=468153#c164">bug issued in 2015 about the topic&lt;/a>. Here is the TL,DR (from March 2016):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My list of GitHub tips and third-party apps</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/09/03/my-list-of-github-tips-and-third-party-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 11:42:19 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/09/03/my-list-of-github-tips-and-third-party-apps/</guid><description>I work at Thinkific with 20+ other developers (we are hiring for multiple positions) in different codebases. GitHub is part of our toolkit, and I decided to write a post sharing a few Chrome extensions, integrations and third-party apps that help me be productive as an individual contributor and organized as code reviewer and team lead.
Chrome extensions Refined GitHub Sindre Sorhus extension brings a massive list of improvements to GitHub UI and many of them have become part of the product after a bit.</description></item><item><title>Newsletters to subscribe</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/05/14/newsletters-to-subscribe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 23:54:26 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/05/14/newsletters-to-subscribe/</guid><description>In the last years, newsletters became more and more popular. Along with Twitter and RSS, it is one of my favourite ways to keep me updated it. Here are the ones I follow:
Software Lead Weekly – if you are a team lead, engineer manager, CTO you will like this one. Worth to mention their Slack group. Changelog – independently of your stack, Changelog is a rich newsletter with interviews and tool suggestions.</description></item><item><title>It Doesn't Have to Be Crazy at Work and Joy, Inc.: How We Built a Workplace People Love reviews</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/01/23/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work-and-joy-inc-how-we-built-a-workplace-people-love-reviews/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 04:41:05 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/01/23/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work-and-joy-inc-how-we-built-a-workplace-people-love-reviews/</guid><description>In the last couple of months, I read It Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Have to Be Crazy at Work and Joy, Inc.: How We Built a Workplace People Love. They both cover how two successful tech companies operate their activities in a very proud way. Reading these books can be inspirational for your company but at the same time, it does require a grain of salt.
In It Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Have to Be Crazy at Work, David Heinemeier Hansson / Jason Fried share how they keep Basecamp processes and team calm.</description></item><item><title>Engineering Manager Readme</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/06/24/engineering-manager-readme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 20:33:07 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/06/24/engineering-manager-readme/</guid><description>&lt;p>Being a Team Lead requires more than tech skills: you interact daily with people and it is quite challenging building stronger relationships and improving employees onboarding. The following document is my People Lead Readme (sometimes known as Manager Readme), where I talk about me and I share my expectations on people and on the product.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what">What?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This document is an extended introduction to what I value and believe in as a team leader and software developer. It is also a quick introduction about myself and how I work.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This document doesn&amp;rsquo;t replace getting to know each other through 1:1s and day-to-day chats. As I said before, it is an introduction.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This document applies only to me, and in no way should be considered to apply to any other team lead or manager at Thinkific – even though we think in similar ways sometimes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you feel like I am not acting like I describe here, please let me know.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you are curious why this document exists in the first place: there is a newsletter called &lt;a href="http://softwareleadweekly.com/">SoftwareLeadWeekly&lt;/a> (recommended) and managers &lt;a href="http://softwareleadweekly.com/issues/271">share their own readme&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> there. After seeing several documents, I decided to write my own.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Another dotfiles repository</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/06/16/another-dotfiles-repository/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 18:42:55 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/06/16/another-dotfiles-repository/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few days weeks I got a MacBook Air as secondary machine. Since its SSD is smaller than my main Mac I couldn’t use Time Machine. It was definitely a good time to finally create my &lt;a href="https://github.com/leonardofaria/dotfiles">dotfiles&lt;/a> repository. My repository is based in &lt;a href="https://github.com/webpro/dotfiles/">webpro/dotfiles&lt;/a> (you may want to check it out his repo to understand this one if you feel lost).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Testing tools to track my work activity</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/05/06/testing-tools-to-track-my-work-activity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 23:23:30 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/05/06/testing-tools-to-track-my-work-activity/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a few weeks I have been using two tools to map my work activity. Since my work involves &lt;a href="https://www.learningapprentice.com/maker-mode-manager-mode/">manager and maker modes&lt;/a>, I am trying to figure out how much time I spent in each of them and possibly how to remove distractions. A co-worker recommended &lt;a href="https://www.rescuetime.com/ref/1808210">RescueTime&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://wakatime.com/i/cbdf18ed-26ac-43b6-936c-d006efa2bec0">WakaTime&lt;/a> and here are my comments.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="rescuetime">RescueTime&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>RescueTime home page says &lt;em>“With so many distractions and possibilities in your digital life, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get scattered”&lt;/em> – yes, I know – and &lt;em>“RescueTime helps you understand your daily habits so you can focus and be more productive”&lt;/em>. Yes, they really helped me understand my daily habits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#deletefacebook and social media effects on me</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/03/28/deletefacebook-social-media-effects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 23:13:28 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/03/28/deletefacebook-social-media-effects/</guid><description>&lt;p>This week #deletefacebook was a trending topic everywhere after all the Cambridge Analytica scandal. Lots of people deleted their accounts, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/23/17156402/elon-musk-deleted-tesla-and-spacex-facebook-pages-twitter-challenge">Elon Musk&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/20/17145200/brian-acton-delete-facebook-whatsapp">WhatsApp co-founder Brian Acton&lt;/a>. I didn&amp;rsquo;t delete my account but one thing that I did in the middle of February was deleting the app from my iPhone – which is a good step anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am not deleting my account because I still need Facebook to reach a few people from my previous companies/schools. I used Facebook groups a lot in the past when I was dealing with immigration and unfortunately, it is difficult to find a replacement for this functionality. Forums and lists are not a thing since Facebook absorbed everything on its island.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-can-i-do">What can I do?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If I can&amp;rsquo;t delete my Facebook account, I may have some way to undo my friendship with them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on building components libraries</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/02/04/thoughts-building-components-libraries/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 16:24:53 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/02/04/thoughts-building-components-libraries/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few months ago we started using React at &lt;a href="https://thinkific.com">Thinkific&lt;/a>. One of the challenges of using React is creating reusable components not only from a look and feel perspective but also shareable in different projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t create this concept of elements (or components) library. To be honest, there are podcasts, courses, and examples everywhere about it but how to even start it? When you start creating a project from scratch you face several questions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How to style components? Sass? Stylus? styled-components?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to show the elements?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to build the library? Babel? Webpack?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to publish the library? To NPM or not NPM?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to use integrations and CI in your favour?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Lots of decisions and you may not know all the answers. Startup Life™ doesn&amp;rsquo;t let you do whatever you want – everything has a cost and a trade-off. Why am I talking all this story? Because I wanted to share my thoughts about it and I created a &lt;a href="https://github.com/leonardofaria/leozera-ui">&lt;strong>repository to document&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> what we are doing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sick Picks: Podcasts</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/01/23/sick-picks-podcasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 02:46:07 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/01/23/sick-picks-podcasts/</guid><description>I am huge fan of podcasts. It is always nice to hear people&amp;rsquo;s thoughts, struggles, jokes and sick picks. Here is my short list of development-related podcasts.
Syntax: Wes Bos and Scott Tolinski talk about webdevelopment. You can expect lots of Javascript – especially React – and CSS here. Developer Tea: plenty of episodes about the developer career. Off the top of my head I would recommend the episode about Experienced Developers and Impostor Syndrome.</description></item><item><title>Useful apps that I use daily – 2017 edition</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2017/12/14/useful-apps-that-i-use-daily-2017-edition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 05:09:20 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2017/12/14/useful-apps-that-i-use-daily-2017-edition/</guid><description>&lt;p>2 years ago I wrote a &lt;a href="https://leonardofaria.net/2015/09/17/useful-apps-that-i-use-daily/">post&lt;/a> about my tooling and here I am again, 2017 edition. I decided to write again because I keep listening to podcasts with Sick Picks and I also have my Sick Picks :)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dev-tools">Dev tools&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="editor-atom">Editor: Atom&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I have been using Atom for a while. Despite I started testing VS Code in the latest months, I returned to Atom because VS Code doesn&amp;rsquo;t separate &lt;a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/vscode/issues/25986">UI theme from syntax theme&lt;/a> – you may not care about this, but I am a fan of a light UI and a dark code highlight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/leonardofaria/982b8055af2d6d02116b03950bbf0583">&lt;img src="https://leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/screenshot-atom.png" alt="My Atom">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are the packages that I have installed:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Github webinars</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2017/12/04/github-webinars/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 15:44:53 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2017/12/04/github-webinars/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many of us use Github daily however we usually don&amp;rsquo;t use all its features. On the latest months, its team released a few webinars about how Github uses Github. More than showing the web interface, they talked about their culture and their workflows. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m adding the links to the webinars with a few notes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloudready or how to get a Chrome OS in a non-Chromebook laptop</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/12/29/cloudready-or-how-to-get-a-chrome-os-in-a-non-chromebook-laptop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 16:36:55 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/12/29/cloudready-or-how-to-get-a-chrome-os-in-a-non-chromebook-laptop/</guid><description>Few months ago I saw in The Verge a post about CloudReady. CloudReady is a remake of Chromium OS ready to go in old PCs or Macs. The company behind the product sells its solutions/support to organizations interested in keeping using their hardware. It&amp;rsquo;s really interesting.
I am writing this post because my wife has an old Samsung laptop and I finally found a time to give a chance to CloudReady.</description></item><item><title>Another Meetup presentation</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/12/02/another-meetup-presentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 16:41:57 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/12/02/another-meetup-presentation/</guid><description>In yesterday Code &amp;amp; Coffee Meetup I talked about how Web APIs can improve User Experience. I watched Zeno Rocha talking about it few months ago then I decided to study/share the subject.
Here are my slides and the example repository that I created for the event.</description></item><item><title>Serving raw files directly from Github</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/08/06/serving-raw-files-directly-from-github/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 20:49:30 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/08/06/serving-raw-files-directly-from-github/</guid><description>We usually create HTML files in our Github repositories, but how to show this data in the browser? RawGit is a solution to serve files with the correct content types.
Example: The WordPress readme.html file can be shown in the following URL:
https://rawgit.com/WordPress/WordPress/master/readme.html You only need to follow the formula:
https://rawgit.com/USER/REPOSITORY/BRANCH/file.html The advantage of using RawGit over Github Pages is that RawGit works with all branches, while Github Pages requires a gh-pages branch.</description></item><item><title>My first Meetup presentation</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/06/24/my-first-meetup-presentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 11:41:13 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/06/24/my-first-meetup-presentation/</guid><description>Last week I presented in Code &amp;amp; Coffee about WordPress and Gulp. In my 10 minutes talk, I explained briefly what is Gulp and how its tasks can save our time.
Here are my slides and the example repository that I created for the event.
Update: video</description></item><item><title>Resolving slow loading of local virtualhosts on Chrome</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/03/13/resolving-slow-loading-of-local-virtualhosts-on-chrome/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 14:38:56 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/03/13/resolving-slow-loading-of-local-virtualhosts-on-chrome/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve in my development mac different virtualhosts, using .local or .wp TLDs. Opening these address in Chrome are slow – about 3 seconds ‘resolving address&amp;rsquo;. This situation doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen in Safari or Firefox. Here is my typical &lt;code>/etc/hosts&lt;/code> configuration:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replace git author using shell script</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/02/02/replace-git-author-using-shell-script/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 02:22:56 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/02/02/replace-git-author-using-shell-script/</guid><description>This is an old trick that saved me several times. Sometimes people forget to setup their name and email information. The following script is useful to fix mistakes:
#!/bin/sh git filter-branch -f --env-filter &amp;#39; an=&amp;#34;$GIT_AUTHOR_NAME&amp;#34; am=&amp;#34;$GIT_AUTHOR_EMAIL&amp;#34; cn=&amp;#34;$GIT_COMMITTER_NAME&amp;#34; cm=&amp;#34;$GIT_COMMITTER_EMAIL&amp;#34; if [ &amp;#34;$GIT_COMMITTER_EMAIL&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;old@email.com&amp;#34; ] then cn=&amp;#34;New author name&amp;#34; cm=&amp;#34;new@email.com&amp;#34; fi export GIT_AUTHOR_NAME=&amp;#34;$an&amp;#34; export GIT_AUTHOR_EMAIL=&amp;#34;$am&amp;#34; export GIT_COMMITTER_NAME=&amp;#34;$cn&amp;#34; export GIT_COMMITTER_EMAIL=&amp;#34;$cm&amp;#34; &amp;#39; echo &amp;#34;Run after&amp;#34; echo &amp;#34;git push origin +master:master&amp;#34;</description></item><item><title>Shell script para gravar áudio da Web</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/01/29/shell-script-para-gravar-audio-da-web/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 20:06:38 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/01/29/shell-script-para-gravar-audio-da-web/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://leonardofaria.net/2016/01/26/shell-script-for-audio-recording/">This post is also available in English.&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Um dos meus programas de rádio favoritos é o Central 98, da &lt;a href="http://98live.com.br/">98FM&lt;/a> (de Belo Horizonte). Ele começa às 10h da manhã e devido a diferença de 6h de fuso horário eu não consigo ouví-lo ao vivo. Então, criei um shell script para gravar o programa e assim posso ouvi-lo no meu tempo livre.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shell script for audio recording</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/01/26/shell-script-for-audio-recording/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 18:13:43 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2016/01/26/shell-script-for-audio-recording/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://leonardofaria.net/2016/01/29/shell-script-para-gravar-audio-da-web/">Esse artigo está disponível em português.&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my favourite radio shows happens every day at 10 AM (Brasilia Timezone). I was unable to listen to it because the time zones. Then, I created the following small shell script to record the show and then I can listen to it in my free time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>the ink magazine</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/12/12/the-ink-magazine/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 21:12:26 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/12/12/the-ink-magazine/</guid><description>the ink magazine was an assignment of my HTML &amp;amp; CSS classes in the Web and Mobile App Design and Development program, performed in Langara College.
The students was supposed to create a magazine responsive layout using HTML/CSS. (I usually use Gulp and SASS in my projects, however, I didn&amp;rsquo;t use extra tools in this task).
The source code is available in my Github profile.</description></item><item><title>A new place</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/09/11/a-new-place/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 19:04:24 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/09/11/a-new-place/</guid><description>I have just moved this week to Vancouver. I started my Web and Mobile App Design and Development post-degree in Langara.
Maybe I should write a blog talking about cultural differences between Brazil and Canada, like dozens of Brazilians but I think that those pages show limited or inaccurate point of views.
New times are coming! :)</description></item><item><title>Notice about future</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/05/31/notice-about-future/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 20:29:07 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/05/31/notice-about-future/</guid><description>I stopped writing in this blog for a while. I have been using this blog since 2005 and my absence is justified by live changes.
I am going to write my posts in English but texts in Portuguese could appear eventually. Sorry for eventual grammar mistakes ;)</description></item><item><title>e-Recursos mobile</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2014/11/04/e-recursos-mobile/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 20:50:19 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2014/11/04/e-recursos-mobile/</guid><description>A mais ou menos 1 ano atrás foi publicado a primeira aplicação móvel do Ministério da Previdência Social. Trata-se do e-Recursos, sistema de processo eletrônico de recurso do INSS.
O aplicativo permite a consulta a movimentação do processo bem como o acesso aos documentos que o compõem, desde que o acesso seja realizado pela própria parte interessada. A aplicação está disponível para Android e iOS e já foram mais de 10 mil downloads.</description></item><item><title>TED</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2014/09/02/ted/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 18:13:32 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2014/09/02/ted/</guid><description>Confesso que gosto bastante de assistir os vídeos do TED. Os vídeos são curtos e narram a experiência de pessoas que possivelmente você não encontraria por aí para conversar.
Um dos vídeos que vi recentemente fala em tentar algo novo por 30 dias. 30 dias é geralmente o tempo necessário para assimilar ou abandonar um hábito.
Os próximos 30 dias irão passar, de um jeito ou de outro, então por que não tentar algo novo?</description></item><item><title>URL curta no WordPress</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2009/04/26/url-curta-no-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2009 14:46:56 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2009/04/26/url-curta-no-wordpress/</guid><description>As URLs curtas possuem muitas utilizações por aí, principalmente em microblogs como o Twitter.
&amp;lt;?php function getShortUrl($url) { $tinyurl = file_get_contents(&amp;#34;http://tinyurl.com/api-create.php?url=&amp;#34;.$url); return $tinyurl; } ?&amp;gt; Use a função acima no arquivo functions.php do seu tema. Para exibir o link, crie a seguinte linha no arquivo do post – single.php:
&amp;lt;?php echo &amp;#39;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;&amp;#39;.getShortUrl(get_permalink($post-&amp;gt;ID)).&amp;#39;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;short url&amp;#39;; ?&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Edge Rails no Windows Vista</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2008/09/10/edge-rails-no-windows-vista/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 02:26:40 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2008/09/10/edge-rails-no-windows-vista/</guid><description>Uma das mudanças do Rails 2.2 é não inclusão do bundle do MySQL, responsável por conectar seu projeto ao banco. Mês passado eu postei sobre isso e hoje, ao tentar instalar o gem do MySQL no Windows Vista de um co-worker, me deparei com um problema na DLL libmySQL.dll.
A solução encontrada foi copiar esse arquivo (geralmente em C:\Program Files\MySQL\MySQL Server 4.1\bin) para a pasta bin do Ruby (por exemplo: C:\ruby\bin).</description></item></channel></rss>