<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2018s on Leonardo Faria</title><link>https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/2018/</link><description>Recent content in 2018s on Leonardo Faria</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 20:33:07 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Engineering Manager Readme</title><link>https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/2018/06/24/engineering-manager-readme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 20:33:07 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/2018/06/24/engineering-manager-readme/</guid><description>&lt;p>Being a Team Lead requires more than tech skills: you interact daily with people and it is quite challenging building stronger relationships and improving employees onboarding. The following document is my People Lead Readme (sometimes known as Manager Readme), where I talk about me and I share my expectations on people and on the product.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what">What?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This document is an extended introduction to what I value and believe in as a team leader and software developer. It is also a quick introduction about myself and how I work.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This document doesn&amp;rsquo;t replace getting to know each other through 1:1s and day-to-day chats. As I said before, it is an introduction.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This document applies only to me, and in no way should be considered to apply to any other team lead or manager at Thinkific – even though we think in similar ways sometimes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you feel like I am not acting like I describe here, please let me know.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you are curious why this document exists in the first place: there is a newsletter called &lt;a href="http://softwareleadweekly.com/">SoftwareLeadWeekly&lt;/a> (recommended) and managers &lt;a href="http://softwareleadweekly.com/issues/271">share their own readme&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> there. After seeing several documents, I decided to write my own.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="my-job">My Job&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a team leader, I work for you and my other direct reports, by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Providing context so you and others can be successful, connecting the dots between the company needs and what the individual needs (career growth);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mentoring individual contributors in technologies or business logic that I am familiar with.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t feel like you are stealing my time when you want to talk. Helping you is definitely my job (and one of my top priorities)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="11s">1:1s&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>1:1s are your dedicated time and place to ask me anything and everything. It is your time. If you having nothing to ask, you can use this time for guidance, context, venting, feedback or anything you want to discuss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a few suggestions on how to have a good 1:1:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Take notes about what do you want to talk along the month. It is difficult remembering everything that happened in one month. I may have things to cover but your topics are the priority.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what to talk, I recommend reading &lt;a href="https://knowyourcompany.com/learn/guides/5-how-to-give-feedback/5-how-to-prepare-for-a-one-on-one-meeting-as-an-employee/">How to Prepare for a One-on-One Meeting as an Employee&lt;/a>. There is no reason for being shy since what we discuss is private.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Urgent topics must not wait for a 1:1. Send a message and let&amp;rsquo;s talk.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="personal-quirks">Personal Quirks&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I am available in the office generally between 9 AM and 5 PM. You will know via the Work From Home calendar if I am working from home (usually on Thursdays). We have an open WFH policy and if you are at home please let us know.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I value being on time. We are flexible about when/where you work but attending to events like Town Halls and Stand-ups is not optional. You should be present – unless you have a legitimate reason.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I tend to speak a bit louder and it sounds aggressive sometimes. It is not my intention and when you feel I crossed the line, let me know.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I work with headphones because it helps me to concentrate and I like to listen to the radio/music/podcasts. Sending me a message is probably better than calling my name / tapping my shoulders.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>By the way, sending a message with a brief context of what you want to discuss helps me a lot. I help/work with different people/projects/codebases and as many information you give me in advance as easy is for me to provide what you need.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I may not have all the answers that you need. Sometimes I need to dig the codebase or go for a walk to give you a better answer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Depending on how do you know a particular area or technology, I really expect that you tell me what is your plan, instead of waiting for me to offer a way for you.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I prefer to receive feedback that is actionable and in private.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="about-me">About me&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I wrote my first lines of HTML when I was 12. For a few years, I coded for fun until finding a way to do it full time. I moved to Vancouver / Canada in 2015. A few random facts:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I have a reactive Shih-Tzu called Bento.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I have a small collection of Macs / iDevices, including a Macintosh Plus from 1987.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Another dotfiles repository</title><link>https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/2018/06/16/another-dotfiles-repository/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 18:42:55 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/2018/06/16/another-dotfiles-repository/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few days weeks I got a MacBook Air as secondary machine. Since its SSD is smaller than my main Mac I couldn’t use Time Machine. It was definitely a good time to finally create my &lt;a href="https://github.com/leonardofaria/dotfiles">dotfiles&lt;/a> repository. My repository is based in &lt;a href="https://github.com/webpro/dotfiles/">webpro/dotfiles&lt;/a> (you may want to check it out his repo to understand this one if you feel lost).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/leonardofaria/dotfiles/master/screenshot.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-use-it">How to use it?&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Make sure that you have an updated macOS and Command Line Tools for Xcode: &lt;code>sudo softwareupdate -i -a &amp;amp;&amp;amp; xcode-select --install&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Clone the repo in your home directory: &lt;code>cd ~ &amp;amp; git clone git@github.com:leonardofaria/dotfiles.git ~/.dotfiles&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Run &lt;code>./install.sh&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="a-idwhat_is_installed_10awhat-is-installed">&lt;a id="What_is_installed_10">&lt;/a>What is installed?&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="a-idinstalled_via_brew_12ainstalled-via-brew">&lt;a id="Installed_via_brew_12">&lt;/a>Installed via brew&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Check the description of the less popular apps&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://brewformulas.org/Bats">bats&lt;/a> – Bash Automated Testing System&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/kcrawford/dockutil">dockutil&lt;/a> – Command line tool for managing dock items&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://the.exa.website/">exa&lt;/a> – A modern replacement for &lt;code>ls&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ffmpeg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>git&lt;/li>
&lt;li>git-extras&lt;/li>
&lt;li>htop&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/jakubroztocil/httpie">httpie&lt;/a> – A Modern command line HTTP client&lt;/li>
&lt;li>hugo&lt;/li>
&lt;li>imagemagick&lt;/li>
&lt;li>mysql&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/dylanaraps/neofetch">neofetch&lt;/a> – A command-line system information tool&lt;/li>
&lt;li>nginx&lt;/li>
&lt;li>python3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>sqlite&lt;/li>
&lt;li>tree&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://theunarchiver.com/command-line">unar&lt;/a> – A easy way for unarchiving files&lt;/li>
&lt;li>wget&lt;/li>
&lt;li>wifi-password&lt;/li>
&lt;li>yarn&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="installed-via-brew-cask">Installed via brew cask&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Using brew cask to install Mac app definitely save you a couple hours of browsing&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>appcleaner&lt;/li>
&lt;li>atom&lt;/li>
&lt;li>coconutbattery&lt;/li>
&lt;li>docker&lt;/li>
&lt;li>firefox&lt;/li>
&lt;li>font-meslo-for-powerline&lt;/li>
&lt;li>geekbench&lt;/li>
&lt;li>gitify&lt;/li>
&lt;li>google-chrome&lt;/li>
&lt;li>iterm2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>launchrocket&lt;/li>
&lt;li>sequel-pro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>slack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>sourcetree&lt;/li>
&lt;li>spectacle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>spotify&lt;/li>
&lt;li>tableplus&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the-unarchiver&lt;/li>
&lt;li>transmission&lt;/li>
&lt;li>visual-studio-code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>vlc&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="a-idquick_look_plugins_63aquick-look-plugins">&lt;a id="Quick_Look_plugins_63">&lt;/a>Quick Look plugins&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>betterzip&lt;/li>
&lt;li>qladdict&lt;/li>
&lt;li>qlcolorcode&lt;/li>
&lt;li>qlimagesize&lt;/li>
&lt;li>qlmarkdown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>qlstephen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>qlvideo&lt;/li>
&lt;li>quicklook-csv&lt;/li>
&lt;li>quicklook-json&lt;/li>
&lt;li>suspicious-package&lt;/li>
&lt;li>webpquicklook&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="other-stuff-also-installed">Other stuff also installed&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Node 8 via &lt;code>nvm&lt;/code>, with a few global packages:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/dockly">dockly&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/list-scripts">list-scripts&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/npm-check-updates">npm-check-updates&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/npm-scripts-tree">npm-scripts-tree&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/script-list">script-list&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/space-hogs">space-hogs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/speed-test">speed-test&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ruby 2.5.1 via &lt;code>rvm&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh">Oh my zsh&lt;/a>, with &lt;a href="https://github.com/bhilburn/powerlevel9k">powerlevel9k&lt;/a> theme and git, rails, ruby, npm and osx plugins&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="mac-defaults">Mac Defaults&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are lots of customizable Mac settings. Check &lt;a href="https://github.com/leonardofaria/dotfiles/blob/master/macos/defaults.sh">&lt;code>macos/defaults.sh&lt;/code>&lt;/a> for all details.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="dock-items">Dock items&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can update your dock running: &lt;code>dotfiles dock&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: this will remove all your current dock items.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-idwhat_is_not_done_automatically_100awhat-is-not-done-automatically">&lt;a id="What_is_not_done_automatically_100">&lt;/a>What is not done automatically&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="a-idextra_environment_variables_102aextra-environment-variables">&lt;a id="Extra_environment_variables_102">&lt;/a>Extra environment variables&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Add your extra information environment variables in &lt;code>system/.custom&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-iditerm_2_106aiterm-2">&lt;a id="iTerm_2_106">&lt;/a>iTerm 2&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Open Preferences and in General, check: “Load Preferences from a custom folder or URL”. Point the folder to &lt;code>macos&lt;/code> – There is a file there called &lt;code>com.googlecode.iterm2.plist&lt;/code> with all setup.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Testing tools to track my work activity</title><link>https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/2018/05/06/testing-tools-to-track-my-work-activity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 23:23:30 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/2018/05/06/testing-tools-to-track-my-work-activity/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a few weeks I have been using two tools to map my work activity. Since my work involves &lt;a href="https://www.learningapprentice.com/maker-mode-manager-mode/">manager and maker modes&lt;/a>, I am trying to figure out how much time I spent in each of them and possibly how to remove distractions. A co-worker recommended &lt;a href="https://www.rescuetime.com/ref/1808210">RescueTime&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://wakatime.com/i/cbdf18ed-26ac-43b6-936c-d006efa2bec0">WakaTime&lt;/a> and here are my comments.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="rescuetime">RescueTime&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>RescueTime home page says &lt;em>“With so many distractions and possibilities in your digital life, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get scattered”&lt;/em> – yes, I know – and &lt;em>“RescueTime helps you understand your daily habits so you can focus and be more productive”&lt;/em>. Yes, they really helped me understand my daily habits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am using the Lite version of the app. Every week I get an email like the image below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.rescuetime.com/ref/1808210">&lt;img src="https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/rescuetime-1024x854.jpg" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This email &lt;em>per si&lt;/em> gives me a lot of detailed information. You can schedule when the app tracks your activity – in my case is between 8AM and 6PM, which gives me good coverage of my routine. After a few weeks, you unlock new reports, analyzing communication and most productive vs less productive days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.rescuetime.com/ref/1808210">&lt;img src="https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/rescuetime-report-1024x508.png" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We never know how much time we spend on Slack and similar apps. Now we know the exact impact of these tools in our routines.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="wakatime">WakaTime&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While RescueTime tracks your apps and websites, WakaTime tracks your code activity. You install a plugin in your favourite editor and done! After a while you will receive weekly emails and your data will be organized in a nice dashboard per date/time, project, language, editor and even OS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://wakatime.com/i/cbdf18ed-26ac-43b6-936c-d006efa2bec0">&lt;img src="https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/wakatime-1024x885.jpg" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have no information here to change my work but at least it is interesting to see how I spend my time coding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#deletefacebook and social media effects on me</title><link>https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/2018/03/28/deletefacebook-social-media-effects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 23:13:28 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/2018/03/28/deletefacebook-social-media-effects/</guid><description>&lt;p>This week #deletefacebook was a trending topic everywhere after all the Cambridge Analytica scandal. Lots of people deleted their accounts, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/23/17156402/elon-musk-deleted-tesla-and-spacex-facebook-pages-twitter-challenge">Elon Musk&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/20/17145200/brian-acton-delete-facebook-whatsapp">WhatsApp co-founder Brian Acton&lt;/a>. I didn&amp;rsquo;t delete my account but one thing that I did in the middle of February was deleting the app from my iPhone – which is a good step anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am not deleting my account because I still need Facebook to reach a few people from my previous companies/schools. I used Facebook groups a lot in the past when I was dealing with immigration and unfortunately, it is difficult to find a replacement for this functionality. Forums and lists are not a thing since Facebook absorbed everything on its island.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-can-i-do">What can I do?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If I can&amp;rsquo;t delete my Facebook account, I may have some way to undo my friendship with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/settings">Download a copy of my Facebook data&lt;/a>: I can see now how deep Facebook knows me. I am not sure if this is useful, but is still worth remove data from there? Maybe.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Review apps: 10 years of Facebook and I have 325 apps connected with Facebook. Social login was a good thing until one week ago but now, I don&amp;rsquo;t know how many Cambridge Analytica are around.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/stayfocusd/laankejkbhbdhmipfmgcngdelahlfoji?hl=en">Stayfocused&lt;/a>: this extension blocks websites that I listed after X minutes. Useful not only for Facebook but for all time-consuming pages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Delete the app: I deleted the app already and it is not clear what Facebook knows from your phone however &lt;a href="https://labs.rs/en/">SHARE LAB&lt;/a>, a research team based in Yugoslavia, claims those are the permissions used by Facebook:&lt;br>
&lt;a href="https://labs.rs/en/raw-data-documents-tools/">&lt;img src="https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/facebook-permissions.jpeg" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;br>
&lt;small>Initially saw on &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:6383478848499052544/">Caribé&amp;rsquo;s Linkedin&lt;/a>&lt;/small>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="instagram">Instagram&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Owned by Facebook, Instagram is another social network to &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2017/05/19/health/instagram-worst-social-network-app-young-people-mental-health/index.html">worry about it&lt;/a>. We get stuck in its like/followers game and since they &lt;s>copied Snapchat&lt;/s> released Stories is even more difficult to do not follow your friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JgkvTRz_Alo" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I have decided to use Instagram as a photo album. When I was a child, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have Instagram and my family only took pictures during special times. We had a film camera and a few albums of pictures of weddings and school events. Let me exclude the like factor and FOMO here and share online only what my mom would show in her albums. And also, no more stories. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make my life a soap opera.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on building components libraries</title><link>https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/2018/02/04/thoughts-building-components-libraries/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 16:24:53 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/2018/02/04/thoughts-building-components-libraries/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few months ago we started using React at &lt;a href="https://thinkific.com">Thinkific&lt;/a>. One of the challenges of using React is creating reusable components not only from a look and feel perspective but also shareable in different projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t create this concept of elements (or components) library. To be honest, there are podcasts, courses, and examples everywhere about it but how to even start it? When you start creating a project from scratch you face several questions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How to style components? Sass? Stylus? styled-components?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to show the elements?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to build the library? Babel? Webpack?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to publish the library? To NPM or not NPM?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to use integrations and CI in your favour?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Lots of decisions and you may not know all the answers. Startup Life™ doesn&amp;rsquo;t let you do whatever you want – everything has a cost and a trade-off. Why am I talking all this story? Because I wanted to share my thoughts about it and I created a &lt;a href="https://github.com/leonardofaria/leozera-ui">&lt;strong>repository to document&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> what we are doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="styling">Styling&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.styled-components.com/">styled-components&lt;/a> changed the way we style things however many people still use Sass, especially when they come from Rails (our case for instance).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have something already done in Sass there is no reason for migrating to styled-components. Also, if you keep everything in Sass you can still export your compiled styling easily – like a bootstrap.css.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="showing-elements">Showing elements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://storybook.js.org/">Storybook&lt;/a> is probably the way to go when the topic is showing a component and its properties. My two cents about Storybook:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>They have a &lt;a href="https://now-examples-slackin-nqnzoygycp.now.sh/">really good Slack&lt;/a>, which is an endless source of knowledge.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://storybook.js.org/addons/addon-gallery/">Addons&lt;/a> are pretty useful and it is worth spending a time testing them. &lt;a href="https://github.com/storybooks/storybook/tree/master/addons/knobs">Knobs&lt;/a>, for instance, lets you change props via browser. Quite handy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can host your Storybook using Github Pages. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty straightforward and projects like &lt;a href="https://github.com/tschaub/gh-pages">gh-pages&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://github.com/enriquecaballero/branchsite">branchsite&lt;/a> get job done.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can also host your Storybook using &lt;a href="https://www.netlify.com/">Netlify&lt;/a>. To be honest, this is my favourite approach because you can build the master branch as official documentation and build all additional commits – and get them in &lt;a href="https://github.com/leonardofaria/leozera-ui/pull/1">Pull Requests&lt;/a>!&lt;br>
&lt;img src="https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/netlify.png" alt="Netlify hook in PR">&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="building-the-library">Building the library&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are a few different approaches here. I am using Babel to compile individually the ES6 component and webpack to build everything in one file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the moment I write this post &lt;a href="https://medium.com/webpack/webpack-4-beta-try-it-today-6b1d27d7d7e2">webpack 4&lt;/a> is beta. The performance improvements are quite stunning.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="publishing-the-library">Publishing the library&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Again, there are different approaches to publish the library in NPM. For now, I have a `yarn run publish` command that will bump the version, build the library and publish the built `dist` directory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This approach is quite manual but packages like &lt;a href="https://github.com/sindresorhus/np">np&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://github.com/mgol/npm-bump">npm-bump&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/d4rkr00t/pmm">pmm&lt;/a> can help here. You can also use &lt;code>yarn version&lt;/code> – if you are a yarn person.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="using-integrations">Using integrations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I added CircleCI in the repository since I used to use on daily basis. It runs tests created by jest and after it uploads to Codecov the code coverage. Both CircleCI and Codecov are free for open source projects. Of course you can use &lt;a href="https://travis-ci.org/">Travis CI&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://coveralls.io/">Coveralls&lt;/a>, also free for open source projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One project that I just figured out recently is the &lt;a href="https://nodesecurity.io/">Node Security Platform&lt;/a>. Its job is monitoring vulnerability threatens in your repository. Github also &lt;a href="https://help.github.com/articles/about-security-alerts-for-vulnerable-dependencies/">offers&lt;/a> the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Talking about external dependencies, you may want to consider &lt;a href="https://greenkeeper.io/">Greenkeeper&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://www.dependencies.io/">dependencies.io&lt;/a>. They both monitor your package.json and create individuals Pull Requests to update packages in your repository. The other two options you have are: &lt;code>yarn outdated&lt;/code> or &lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/npm-check-updates">ncu&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/npm-check-updates">&lt;img src="https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/ncu.png" alt="ncu">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last but not least, I like to add a npm script to update the authors file. Here I shoot:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>git log --format='%aN &amp;lt;%aE&amp;gt;' | sort -u --ignore-case | grep -v 'users.noreply.github.com' &amp;gt; AUTHORS.txt &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git commit AUTHORS.txt -m 'Update AUTHORS' || true
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>If you are curious about the &lt;code>git commit AUTHORS.txt -m 'Update AUTHORS' || true&lt;/code>. Not all the time we will modify the text file so I need the &lt;code>|| true&lt;/code> to ensure that the script continues to run even after git reports an error since there is no changes to commit.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="extra-resources">Extra resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I am adding here a few useful links about the topic:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Podcast: &lt;a href="http://frontendhappyhour.com/episodes/top-shelf-style-guides/">Top Shelf Style Guides&lt;/a>: lots of thoughts and links here – this podcast is really good by the way&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Course: &lt;a href="https://www.pluralsight.com/courses/react-creating-reusable-components">Creating Reusable Components&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Mini)-Course: &lt;a href="https://egghead.io/courses/publish-javascript-packages-on-npm">Publish JavaScript packages on NPM&lt;/a> – because this mini-course I found &lt;a href="https://github.com/sindresorhus/np">np&lt;/a>, quoted before.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Website: &lt;a href="http://styleguides.io/">Style Guide&lt;/a> – 496 Website Style Guides and counting…&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inspiration: &lt;a href="https://ant.design/">Ant Design&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inspiration: &lt;a href="https://atlaskit.atlassian.com/">AtlasKit&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inspiration: &lt;a href="https://nikgraf.github.io/belle/">Belly&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inspiration: &lt;a href="http://grommet.io/">Grommet&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inspiration: &lt;a href="https://react.semantic-ui.com/">Semantic UI&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inspiration: &lt;a href="http://reactsymbols.com/">UI React Kit&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Thanks for my co-worker &lt;a href="https://github.com/akiokio">Akio&lt;/a> for helping on this (and &lt;a href="https://github.com/reactjs/reactjs.org/pull/338#issuecomment-346891946">showing Netlify on reactjs.org repository&lt;/a>) and my other folks from Thinkific.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sick Picks: Podcasts</title><link>https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/2018/01/23/sick-picks-podcasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 02:46:07 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://hugo.leonardofaria.net/2018/01/23/sick-picks-podcasts/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am huge fan of podcasts. It is always nice to hear people&amp;rsquo;s thoughts, struggles, jokes and sick picks. Here is my short list of development-related podcasts.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://syntax.fm/">Syntax&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>: Wes Bos and Scott Tolinski talk about webdevelopment. You can expect lots of Javascript – especially React – and CSS here.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://spec.fm/podcasts/developer-tea">Developer Tea&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>: plenty of episodes about the developer career. Off the top of my head I would recommend the episode about &lt;a href="https://spec.fm/podcasts/developer-tea/32884">Experienced Developers and Impostor Syndrome&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://frontendhappyhour.com/">Front End Happy Hour&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>: each episode the hosts toast when someone says a specific word. If you are into style guides, you must head &lt;a href="http://frontendhappyhour.com/episodes/top-shelf-style-guides/">their episode about it&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.se-radio.net/">Software Engineering Radio&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>: I didn&amp;rsquo;t hear a lot of episodes here but it caught my &lt;s>eyes&lt;/s> ears &lt;a href="http://www.se-radio.net/2016/06/se-radio-episode-261-david-heinemeier-hansson-on-the-state-of-rails-monoliths-and-more/">the one with David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/a>, creator of Ruby on Rails.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.vancouvertechpodcast.ca/">Vancouver Tech Podcast&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>: last but not least, I&amp;rsquo;ve been living in Vancouver for more than 2 years and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to hear the local tech scene.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>What are your favourite podcasts? Let me know in the comments :)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>