<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2018s on Leonardo Faria</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/</link><description>Recent content in 2018s on Leonardo Faria</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 20:33:07 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leonardofaria.net/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Engineering Manager Readme</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/06/24/engineering-manager-readme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 20:33:07 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/06/24/engineering-manager-readme/</guid><description>&lt;p>Being a Team Lead requires more than tech skills: you interact daily with people and it is quite challenging building stronger relationships and improving employees onboarding. The following document is my People Lead Readme (sometimes known as Manager Readme), where I talk about me and I share my expectations on people and on the product.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what">What?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This document is an extended introduction to what I value and believe in as a team leader and software developer. It is also a quick introduction about myself and how I work.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This document doesn&amp;rsquo;t replace getting to know each other through 1:1s and day-to-day chats. As I said before, it is an introduction.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This document applies only to me, and in no way should be considered to apply to any other team lead or manager at Thinkific – even though we think in similar ways sometimes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you feel like I am not acting like I describe here, please let me know.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you are curious why this document exists in the first place: there is a newsletter called &lt;a href="http://softwareleadweekly.com/">SoftwareLeadWeekly&lt;/a> (recommended) and managers &lt;a href="http://softwareleadweekly.com/issues/271">share their own readme&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> there. After seeing several documents, I decided to write my own.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Another dotfiles repository</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/06/16/another-dotfiles-repository/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 18:42:55 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/06/16/another-dotfiles-repository/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few days weeks I got a MacBook Air as secondary machine. Since its SSD is smaller than my main Mac I couldn’t use Time Machine. It was definitely a good time to finally create my &lt;a href="https://github.com/leonardofaria/dotfiles">dotfiles&lt;/a> repository. My repository is based in &lt;a href="https://github.com/webpro/dotfiles/">webpro/dotfiles&lt;/a> (you may want to check it out his repo to understand this one if you feel lost).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Testing tools to track my work activity</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/05/06/testing-tools-to-track-my-work-activity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 23:23:30 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/05/06/testing-tools-to-track-my-work-activity/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a few weeks I have been using two tools to map my work activity. Since my work involves &lt;a href="https://www.learningapprentice.com/maker-mode-manager-mode/">manager and maker modes&lt;/a>, I am trying to figure out how much time I spent in each of them and possibly how to remove distractions. A co-worker recommended &lt;a href="https://www.rescuetime.com/ref/1808210">RescueTime&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://wakatime.com/i/cbdf18ed-26ac-43b6-936c-d006efa2bec0">WakaTime&lt;/a> and here are my comments.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="rescuetime">RescueTime&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>RescueTime home page says &lt;em>“With so many distractions and possibilities in your digital life, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get scattered”&lt;/em> – yes, I know – and &lt;em>“RescueTime helps you understand your daily habits so you can focus and be more productive”&lt;/em>. Yes, they really helped me understand my daily habits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>#deletefacebook and social media effects on me</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/03/28/deletefacebook-social-media-effects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 23:13:28 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/03/28/deletefacebook-social-media-effects/</guid><description>&lt;p>This week #deletefacebook was a trending topic everywhere after all the Cambridge Analytica scandal. Lots of people deleted their accounts, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/23/17156402/elon-musk-deleted-tesla-and-spacex-facebook-pages-twitter-challenge">Elon Musk&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/20/17145200/brian-acton-delete-facebook-whatsapp">WhatsApp co-founder Brian Acton&lt;/a>. I didn&amp;rsquo;t delete my account but one thing that I did in the middle of February was deleting the app from my iPhone – which is a good step anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am not deleting my account because I still need Facebook to reach a few people from my previous companies/schools. I used Facebook groups a lot in the past when I was dealing with immigration and unfortunately, it is difficult to find a replacement for this functionality. Forums and lists are not a thing since Facebook absorbed everything on its island.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-can-i-do">What can I do?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If I can&amp;rsquo;t delete my Facebook account, I may have some way to undo my friendship with them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on building components libraries</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/02/04/thoughts-building-components-libraries/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 16:24:53 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/02/04/thoughts-building-components-libraries/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few months ago we started using React at &lt;a href="https://thinkific.com">Thinkific&lt;/a>. One of the challenges of using React is creating reusable components not only from a look and feel perspective but also shareable in different projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t create this concept of elements (or components) library. To be honest, there are podcasts, courses, and examples everywhere about it but how to even start it? When you start creating a project from scratch you face several questions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How to style components? Sass? Stylus? styled-components?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to show the elements?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to build the library? Babel? Webpack?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to publish the library? To NPM or not NPM?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to use integrations and CI in your favour?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Lots of decisions and you may not know all the answers. Startup Life™ doesn&amp;rsquo;t let you do whatever you want – everything has a cost and a trade-off. Why am I talking all this story? Because I wanted to share my thoughts about it and I created a &lt;a href="https://github.com/leonardofaria/leozera-ui">&lt;strong>repository to document&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> what we are doing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sick Picks: Podcasts</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/01/23/sick-picks-podcasts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 02:46:07 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2018/01/23/sick-picks-podcasts/</guid><description>I am huge fan of podcasts. It is always nice to hear people&amp;rsquo;s thoughts, struggles, jokes and sick picks. Here is my short list of development-related podcasts.
Syntax: Wes Bos and Scott Tolinski talk about webdevelopment. You can expect lots of Javascript – especially React – and CSS here. Developer Tea: plenty of episodes about the developer career. Off the top of my head I would recommend the episode about Experienced Developers and Impostor Syndrome.</description></item></channel></rss>