<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2019s on Leonardo Faria</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/</link><description>Recent content in 2019s on Leonardo Faria</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 01:40:07 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leonardofaria.net/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A simple Sinatra Auth</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/11/04/a-simple-sinatra-auth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 01:40:07 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/11/04/a-simple-sinatra-auth/</guid><description>Imagine you want to protect the content of a website created with Next.js, Hugo or your favourite static site generator. Github doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer this feature or Netlify offers authentication only in their paid plans. Decided to create something simple with Sinatra, TailwindCSS and ready to go in Heroku.</description></item><item><title>Creating a website for my Apple Collection</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/10/17/creating-a-website-for-my-apple-collection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:36:30 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/10/17/creating-a-website-for-my-apple-collection/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/collection.jpg" alt="Part of the collection">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A while ago I started an Apple Collection. After a few laptops and a few iDevices, I decided that I should start collecting info about my iThings. In the beginning, I created a gist containing model, serial number, how did I get the device, minimum/maximum OS, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The list kept going bigger and bigger and the content started looking messy. The natural way to organize my data would be inside a SQL database, with the information distributed in columns. After organizing the information in tables, I would create a graphQL API (the one cool kids use these days) to give me the data needed to populate my UI – probably written in React, compiled with Babel and packed with webpack.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Forcing the usage of yarn (and at a specific version)</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/10/11/forcing-the-usage-of-yarn-and-at-a-specific-version/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:40:46 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/10/11/forcing-the-usage-of-yarn-and-at-a-specific-version/</guid><description>&lt;p>People and organizations often have preferences for a specific package manager. At work, we decided to use Yarn due to emoji support (jk) but how to keep everybody using Yarn? &lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can use the &lt;a href="https://docs.npmjs.com/misc/scripts">preinstall hook&lt;/a> to check if the user run &lt;code>npm install&lt;/code>or &lt;code>yarn install&lt;/code>. Here is one example:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-js" data-lang="js">&lt;span style="color:#d14">&amp;#34;scripts&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span> {
&lt;span style="color:#d14">&amp;#34;preinstall&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#d14">&amp;#34;node -e \&amp;#34;if(process.env.npm_execpath.indexOf(&amp;#39;yarn&amp;#39;) === -1) throw new Error(&amp;#39;You must use Yarn to install, not NPM&amp;#39;)\&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span>,
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Disabling autofill in Chrome</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/10/02/disabling-autofill-in-chrome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 16:58:52 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/10/02/disabling-autofill-in-chrome/</guid><description>&lt;p>Autofill in form elements is a very useful feature in browsers. Creating new accounts or shopping in an online store are examples of this feature saving us time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, the autofill feature can be a problem for SaaS products. Imagine that you want to edit the email address of one of your users. You hit edit in one screen and once you get a form with your user data Chrome will replace their email to your email. This is not a good user experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MDN has an article showing “How to turn off form autocompletion”. The solution is using the autocomplete attribute with an off value. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in Chrome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Digging in Stackoverflow and Google results, I found a &lt;a href="https://bugs.chromium.org/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=468153#c164">bug issued in 2015 about the topic&lt;/a>. Here is the TL,DR (from March 2016):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My list of GitHub tips and third-party apps</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/09/03/my-list-of-github-tips-and-third-party-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 11:42:19 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/09/03/my-list-of-github-tips-and-third-party-apps/</guid><description>I work at Thinkific with 20+ other developers (we are hiring for multiple positions) in different codebases. GitHub is part of our toolkit, and I decided to write a post sharing a few Chrome extensions, integrations and third-party apps that help me be productive as an individual contributor and organized as code reviewer and team lead.
Chrome extensions Refined GitHub Sindre Sorhus extension brings a massive list of improvements to GitHub UI and many of them have become part of the product after a bit.</description></item><item><title>Newsletters to subscribe</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/05/14/newsletters-to-subscribe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 23:54:26 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/05/14/newsletters-to-subscribe/</guid><description>In the last years, newsletters became more and more popular. Along with Twitter and RSS, it is one of my favourite ways to keep me updated it. Here are the ones I follow:
Software Lead Weekly – if you are a team lead, engineer manager, CTO you will like this one. Worth to mention their Slack group. Changelog – independently of your stack, Changelog is a rich newsletter with interviews and tool suggestions.</description></item><item><title>It Doesn't Have to Be Crazy at Work and Joy, Inc.: How We Built a Workplace People Love reviews</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/01/23/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work-and-joy-inc-how-we-built-a-workplace-people-love-reviews/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 04:41:05 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2019/01/23/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work-and-joy-inc-how-we-built-a-workplace-people-love-reviews/</guid><description>In the last couple of months, I read It Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Have to Be Crazy at Work and Joy, Inc.: How We Built a Workplace People Love. They both cover how two successful tech companies operate their activities in a very proud way. Reading these books can be inspirational for your company but at the same time, it does require a grain of salt.
In It Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Have to Be Crazy at Work, David Heinemeier Hansson / Jason Fried share how they keep Basecamp processes and team calm.</description></item></channel></rss>