<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>career on Leonardo Faria</title><link>https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/tags/career/</link><description>Recent content in career on Leonardo Faria</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 01:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building Emergenetics Explorer</title><link>https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/2022/04/25/building-emergenetics-explorer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/2022/04/25/building-emergenetics-explorer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last year I built a tool to visualize data from Emergenetics Profile. In this post, you will learn what is Emergenetics, why and how I built &lt;a href="https://emergenetics-explorer.leonardofaria.net">Emergenetics Explorer&lt;/a>, a data visualization tool in my spare time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/emergenetics-explorer-intro.png" alt="Screenshot of Emergenetics Explorer">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>TL, DR&lt;/strong>: See the application live at &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://emergenetics-explorer.leonardofaria.net">https://emergenetics-explorer.leonardofaria.net&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> and keep reading the post for details. The post is good, I promise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disclaimer&lt;/strong>: I am not affiliated with Emergenetics. I am genuinely curious about psychology and how we interact with each other, at work and outside work.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-emergenetics">What is Emergenetics&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My previous company uses Emergenetics assessments as a way to learn how to work better. According to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emergenetics_International">Wikipedia&lt;/a>, &lt;em>Emergenetics International uses psychometric research and behavioral studies to advise and consult with businesses and individuals on how to assess human capital&lt;/em>. Their Emergenetics Profile is an &lt;em>assessment test to designate individuals by four thinking attributes, analytical, structural, social and conceptual, and three behavioral attributes, expressiveness, assertiveness and flexibility.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An Emergenetics Profile looks like this (&lt;a href="https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/pub/emergenetics-sample-profile.pdf">full width&lt;/a>):&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;iframe src="https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/pub/emergenetics-sample-profile.pdf" class="w-full" style="height: 60vh">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>From what I understand (from an analytical/structural brain), there is no right or wrong profile. People are different and as more diverse they are, the better. With the information of the profile, you can understand better your signs of brilliance, challenges and how you prefer others to communicate with you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="idea">Idea&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since Emergenetics is very present in the company&amp;rsquo;s culture, people started building charts showing where their team members fit in the analytical, structural, social and conceptual spectrums. Something like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/emergenetics-explorer-chart.png" alt="Chart">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After seeing the second manually-made chart I decided to create my dynamically-made Emergenetics chart. After talking to a few people to get the data (the company doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an API), I started coding.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="execution">Execution&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My initial idea was to list all people&amp;rsquo;s profiles and then the user could select the profiles of their interest. People should be able to see all profiles of a specific manager and have an option to download the chart for future use (team introductions for example).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/emergenetics-explorer.jpg" alt="Emergenetics Explorer">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The data came from a CSV file, updated once a month after more employees took the Emergenetics assessment. I persisted the results in a database synced with BambooHR data. Using the BambooHR API here was very important because I could present the employee Emergenetics results along with their other data (profile photo and manager).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-non-emergenetics-portion-of-the-emergenetics-explorer">The non-Emergenetics portion of the Emergenetics Explorer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After I finished this MVP version of the application, I thought it would be cool to add new features to the &amp;ldquo;product&amp;rdquo;. The first of them was a &lt;a href="https://emergenetics-explorer.leonardofaria.net/directory">Directory page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/emergenetics-explorer-directory.jpg" alt="Directory page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Directory page lists all employees and their basic info (title, division, department, location, manager). You can also check their individual Emergenetics profiles.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="map">Map&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Since I also had the name of the city, state and country of employees, I thought it would be cool to show where employees live in a &lt;a href="https://emergenetics-explorer.leonardofaria.net/world">map&lt;/a>. Since the company became remote-first, people liked this a lot to get to know where their colleagues live.&lt;/p>
&lt;video class="h-auto" controls autoplay="autoplay">
&lt;source src="https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/emergenetics-explorer-world.mp4" type="video/mp4">
&lt;/video>
&lt;h3 id="radar">Radar&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A designer created a radar version of the Emergenetics data in Figma (I have no idea how) and I added similar visualization in the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/emergenetics-explorer-radar.png" alt="Radar">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This radar chart was quite interesting to see with live data: it showed how people with specific job titles had similar profiles (too social or too analytical).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="technical-details">Technical details&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This project was also a good excuse to work with tech that I was not working with at my job. Generally speaking, it is a Next.js TypeScript project deployed to Vercel. To make this project reality, I wrote a small API parser in Ruby and played with Google Maps and data visualization tools. I also implemented UI elements (buttons, modals, etc) with the same company&amp;rsquo;s look and feel in Tailwind CSS.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="live">Live&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can see the application live at &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://emergenetics-explorer.leonardofaria.net">https://emergenetics-explorer.leonardofaria.net&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>. This environment uses sample data created with Faker. To see the data, you need to authenticate with any Google account (in the real environment, only users of a specific domain can see the real data).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The path to Staff Engineer</title><link>https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/2021/11/08/the-path-to-staff-engineer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/2021/11/08/the-path-to-staff-engineer/</guid><description>&lt;p>What happens after you are a Senior Engineer in a startup? How do you align your career goals with what the company you work for needs? In this post, I share my personal experience while I also talk about the &lt;a href="http://staffeng.com">Staff Engineer book&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/staff-eng-cover.png" alt="Architect&amp;rsquo;s Weekly Calendar">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the last five years, I have worked in different roles at Thinkific (by the way, &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/thnk-careers">we are hiring&lt;/a>): I started as a Full-stack Developer, and then I was Team Lead for three years. The Team Lead role was great, and I had great support from the organization, but it was not for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moving back to a Technical track of my career, I found the Staff Engineer book written by Wilson Larson, which helped me a lot how to see my role and my potential. The book covers the different types of Staff+ titles we see in this industry (Staff Engineer, Principal Engineer, Architect, and others) and contains interviews with fourteen professionals who share their career trajectories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can &lt;a href="https://staffeng.com/book">buy Staff Engineer&lt;/a> as an ebook, audiobook, or physical copy, and if my post doesn&amp;rsquo;t convince you, listen to these &lt;a href="https://linearb.io/blog/will-larson-staff-engineer/">two&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/5U878ZRPNhh9dwBfyuABn1?si=It4Vaa6TTWOVHCKF3UA6Tg&amp;amp;nd=1">podcasts&lt;/a> about the content of the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next, I will share a few topics of the book along with my personal experiences.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="archetypes">Archetypes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The book starts by identifying the different archetypes of Staff Engineers. I previously noticed how my colleagues act in different ways in their projects and teams:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Tech Lead&lt;/strong> guides the approach and execution of a particular team;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Architect&lt;/strong> is responsible for the direction, quality, and strategy within an area;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Solver&lt;/strong> dips deep into complex problems and finds an appropriate path forward;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Right-Hand&lt;/strong> borrows executive scope and authority to operate particularly complex organizations.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The archetypes do not necessarily reflect a job title, but the Architect one sounded like what I was doing at work. The book has a &amp;ldquo;typical calendar example&amp;rdquo; for each role, and his Architect&amp;rsquo;s Weekly Calendar looked pretty similar to mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/staff-eng-architect-calendar.png" alt="Architect&amp;rsquo;s Weekly Calendar">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The calendar looks very busy compared to an Individual Contributor calendar. It reflects that Staff Engineers are in a leadership position. They influence people, not like a Team Lead or Engineer Manager, but differently: with technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-the-title">Getting the title&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The book also covers how to &amp;ldquo;get there&amp;rdquo;. It is a combination of different factors, and I will comment on some of the mentioned in the book, starting with Staff Project.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="staff-projects">Staff projects&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is not a promotion requirement, but delivering a Staff project is a popular step around reaching a Staff+ role. Staff projects are typically:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Complex and ambiguous: the project might start with only one unclear statement, and from there, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to identify a concrete approach that works;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Numerous and divided stakeholders: the complexity can also happen in the organizational alignment around both the problem and the solution;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Highly visible: the kind of project that leadership talks about it in their all-company meetings. Any failure or success will be visible.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a Staff project to move to an architecture role; however, I delivered a complex project with the characteristics above during my Team Lead years.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="promotion-packet">Promotion packet&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Once you identify why you want the role - &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;this is not a faster Senior Engineer&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> - the next step is writing a promotion packet. Organizations will do this in different ways, but mainly the outcome is mapping your impact as a professional and identifying areas or skills that you can develop in the next while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The promotion packet is a living document. Review it with your manager once you have the first version, and periodically check/update it to follow your progress towards a career change.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="finding-your-sponsor">Finding your sponsor&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;The most important member of the team guiding your promotion is you yourself&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> is a quote I couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more. Nobody will drive your career for you, but it is crucial to find people that will support your journey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your direct manager will be the person to advocate for your promotion and the one having honest conversations about the gaps you need to fill to become a better professional. They may/may not have worked with someone aspiring to the same careers goals that you have, and for that, invest in other relationships.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="get-in-the-room-and-stay-there">Get in the room, and stay there&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This chapter is great no matter the area you work or the title you have. The content is &lt;a href="https://staffeng.com/guides/getting-in-the-room">available online&lt;/a> and here is a short summary of the main points:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>There is no single &amp;ldquo;room&amp;rdquo; to enter&lt;/strong>: entering rooms will be an ongoing, iterative careers challenge. It might be a sprint pre-planning with your tech lead, a quarterly planning meeting, or an architecture review.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are some strategies to increase your value &amp;ldquo;to the room&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Stay aligned with your manager: being on the same page as your manager is something that many take a while to comprehend;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optimize for the group: optimize your message for others build trust and confidence in your judgment;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Speak clearly and concisely: good advice no matter what occasion you are interacting with other human beings;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Be low friction: learn how to navigate difficult conversations effectively, and you&amp;rsquo;re more likely to be involved;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Come prepared: good advice no matter what occasion you are interacting with other human beings;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Focus and be present: good advice no matter what occasion you are interacting with other human beings;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Volunteer for low-status tasks: being helpful, especially for not exciting tasks, is an underestimated skill.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="being-visible">Being visible&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The last topic about the book I want to highlight here is visibility. Visibility is crucial in this type of role, and there are ways to improve visibility in the workspace:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Executive visibility:&lt;/strong> develop relationships beyond your manager;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>External visibility:&lt;/strong> have a blog/podcast and speak in a meetup/conference creates visibility for yourself and your work;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Internal visibility:&lt;/strong> work on things that matter is the best way to create internal visibility, however a few other things that can help you, including writing long-lived documents (ex. architecture docs), leading company events (ex. architecture reviews, company all-hands), contributing to your company&amp;rsquo;s blog and attending/hosting office hours for your team or organization.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I am a true believer in external visibility; otherwise, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be writing about development here since 2005 or speaking at meetups (even without a polished English) since 2016. In different organizations I worked with, I had written docs, led company events, and attended/hosted events.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="stories">Stories&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Each story of a Staff or Principal is fascinating to read. My favourite snippet, which is very similar to what I was doing before reading the book, is from &lt;a href="https://sylormiller.com">Katie Sylor-Miller&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a frontend architect, but by far the main thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing lately is SQL, because I&amp;rsquo;m doing a lot of data analysis. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at our performance metrics to figure out where the areas for improvement are, and what would be the most impactful issues to fix to improve performance and business metrics. I will write little bits of JS or PHP here and there, but it&amp;rsquo;s mostly to help unblock teams or to run small performance-related experiments.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="conclusions">Conclusions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Figuring out what to do in our careers is hard, but there is help out there. For a while, I stayed in the &amp;ldquo;manager path&amp;rdquo; then I returned to the &amp;ldquo;technical path&amp;rdquo; with the support of my [great] manager and research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope that the experience I shared here and Larson&amp;rsquo;s book can help you identify how to navigate your career development. Share your thoughts in the comments!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mentoring Framework</title><link>https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/2020/06/01/the-mentoring-framework/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/2020/06/01/the-mentoring-framework/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last October I created a Mentoring Framework at work. The goal was creating a project from scratch using Ruby on Rails and in this journey, learning more about Ruby, Frontend, Project Management and Git, Databases and DevOps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This Mentoring Framework is similar to what bootcamps do but the difference here is I am sharing a list of suggested features / things to learn and the person can focus in what is important for them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In a nutshell: Goals → Project → Execution → Knowledge (and profit)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The document is divided into 4 main sections: &lt;a href="#before-start">Before start&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#project-ideas">Project ideas&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#execution">Execution&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#examples">Examples&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="#resources">Resources&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-start">Before start&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What are your main goals? For the following list, pick: &amp;ldquo;basic understanding&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;intermediate understanding&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;advanced understanding&amp;rdquo;. This will help to identify where you are going to invest more time and energy.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Learn Ruby / Ruby on Rails&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Learn Frontend&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Learn Project Management and Git&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Learn Databases&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Learn DevOps&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="project-ideas">Project ideas&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once you know your main goals, you need a project. Check the following two ideas:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="book-store">Book store&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Imagine you want to sell books online. What kind of features does a bookstore have?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>List books per title&lt;/li>
&lt;li>List books per authors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>List books per categories&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Search books&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Buy books&lt;/li>
&lt;li>List your orders&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="pet-adoption-website">Pet adoption website&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Imagine you want to create a website for an organisation that takes care of animals (in British Columbia we have SPCA). What kind of features does a pet adoption website have?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>List pets per type (dog, cat and others)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>List pets per size (or breed, or age)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>List pets per location&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Search pet per name&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Request an adoption&lt;/li>
&lt;li>List your adoption requests&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="execution">Execution&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once you know your main goals and you have an idea, it is time to work. Check the list of tasks you will be doing:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="learn-ruby-on-rails">Learn Ruby on Rails&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use scaffolds to create your entities (basic understanding) or create your own controllers, models and views (intermediate)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add authentication with Devise (basic understanding) or create your own (intermediate). Or use Devise with Oauth authentication (Facebook, Google, etc - intermediate)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add friendly URLs with a gem (basic) or create your own solution (intermediate)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add search (intermediate)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add tests for all your code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create seeds for your data so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to create manually data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Send email to users (intermediate)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create different user roles (intermediate)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add pagination (basic)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add localization (intermediate)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a tag system (intermediate)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add images (intermediate)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="learn-frontend">Learn Frontend&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use Tailwind CSS (basic) or your own CSS/SASS (intermediate) to create a beautiful layout&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use Turbolinks (advanced / optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add basic animations - ex.: when adding a book in the cart show some animation (advanced/optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add Google Maps in your app (intermediate)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add Google Places in your users&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a carousel with photos&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add Pagination with Ajax or endless pagination (advanced)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="learn-project-management-and-git">Learn Project Management and Git&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use Github Project to organize your features&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use feature branches in Git, create PR for all your features&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="learn-databases">Learn Databases&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Write plain SQL to find relevant information. A few examples:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Find best-sellers authors in the book store&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find the number of orders or pet requests per city&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find which day has more sales&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add charts in your app to expose the data&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="learn-devops">Learn DevOps&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Deploy the website to Heroku (easy/intermediate) or AWS (advanced)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Setup CI in Heroku (easy/intermediate)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add Airbrake to monitor errors in your app (easy)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Buy a domain, set up Cloudflare (advanced/optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="examples">Examples&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-mentoring-framework.png" alt="Website screenshots">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://adopt.spca.bc.ca">SPCA&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.petfinder.com/">Petfinder&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Courses: &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/learning/ruby-on-rails-5-essential-training">Ruby on Rails 5 Essential Training&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/learning/ruby-on-rails-6-essential-training">Ruby on Rails 6 Essential Training&lt;/a> - The first course is longer than the second.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Screencasts: &lt;a href="https://rubytapas.com">RubyTapas&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://gorails.com">GoRails&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Engineering Manager Readme</title><link>https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/2018/06/24/engineering-manager-readme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 20:33:07 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/2018/06/24/engineering-manager-readme/</guid><description>&lt;p>Being a Team Lead requires more than tech skills: you interact daily with people and it is quite challenging building stronger relationships and improving employees onboarding. The following document is my People Lead Readme (sometimes known as Manager Readme), where I talk about me and I share my expectations on people and on the product.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what">What?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This document is an extended introduction to what I value and believe in as a team leader and software developer. It is also a quick introduction about myself and how I work.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This document doesn&amp;rsquo;t replace getting to know each other through 1:1s and day-to-day chats. As I said before, it is an introduction.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This document applies only to me, and in no way should be considered to apply to any other team lead or manager at Thinkific – even though we think in similar ways sometimes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you feel like I am not acting like I describe here, please let me know.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you are curious why this document exists in the first place: there is a newsletter called &lt;a href="http://softwareleadweekly.com/">SoftwareLeadWeekly&lt;/a> (recommended) and managers &lt;a href="http://softwareleadweekly.com/issues/271">share their own readme&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> there. After seeing several documents, I decided to write my own.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="my-job">My Job&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a team leader, I work for you and my other direct reports, by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Providing context so you and others can be successful, connecting the dots between the company needs and what the individual needs (career growth);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mentoring individual contributors in technologies or business logic that I am familiar with.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t feel like you are stealing my time when you want to talk. Helping you is definitely my job (and one of my top priorities)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="11s">1:1s&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>1:1s are your dedicated time and place to ask me anything and everything. It is your time. If you having nothing to ask, you can use this time for guidance, context, venting, feedback or anything you want to discuss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a few suggestions on how to have a good 1:1:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Take notes about what do you want to talk along the month. It is difficult remembering everything that happened in one month. I may have things to cover but your topics are the priority.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what to talk, I recommend reading &lt;a href="https://knowyourcompany.com/learn/guides/5-how-to-give-feedback/5-how-to-prepare-for-a-one-on-one-meeting-as-an-employee/">How to Prepare for a One-on-One Meeting as an Employee&lt;/a>. There is no reason for being shy since what we discuss is private.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Urgent topics must not wait for a 1:1. Send a message and let&amp;rsquo;s talk.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="personal-quirks">Personal Quirks&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I am available in the office generally between 9 AM and 5 PM. You will know via the Work From Home calendar if I am working from home (usually on Thursdays). We have an open WFH policy and if you are at home please let us know.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I value being on time. We are flexible about when/where you work but attending to events like Town Halls and Stand-ups is not optional. You should be present – unless you have a legitimate reason.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I tend to speak a bit louder and it sounds aggressive sometimes. It is not my intention and when you feel I crossed the line, let me know.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I work with headphones because it helps me to concentrate and I like to listen to the radio/music/podcasts. Sending me a message is probably better than calling my name / tapping my shoulders.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>By the way, sending a message with a brief context of what you want to discuss helps me a lot. I help/work with different people/projects/codebases and as many information you give me in advance as easy is for me to provide what you need.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I may not have all the answers that you need. Sometimes I need to dig the codebase or go for a walk to give you a better answer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Depending on how do you know a particular area or technology, I really expect that you tell me what is your plan, instead of waiting for me to offer a way for you.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I prefer to receive feedback that is actionable and in private.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="about-me">About me&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I wrote my first lines of HTML when I was 12. For a few years, I coded for fun until finding a way to do it full time. I moved to Vancouver / Canada in 2015. A few random facts:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I have a reactive Shih-Tzu called Bento.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I have a small collection of Macs / iDevices, including a Macintosh Plus from 1987.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>