<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2015s on Leonardo Faria</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/</link><description>Recent content in 2015s on Leonardo Faria</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 21:12:26 -0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leonardofaria.net/2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>the ink magazine</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/12/12/the-ink-magazine/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 21:12:26 -0200</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/12/12/the-ink-magazine/</guid><description>the ink magazine was an assignment of my HTML &amp;amp; CSS classes in the Web and Mobile App Design and Development program, performed in Langara College.
The students was supposed to create a magazine responsive layout using HTML/CSS. (I usually use Gulp and SASS in my projects, however, I didn&amp;rsquo;t use extra tools in this task).
The source code is available in my Github profile.</description></item><item><title>My Sublime Text settings</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/10/04/my-sublime-text-settings/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 17:14:16 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/10/04/my-sublime-text-settings/</guid><description>&lt;p>Almost &lt;a href="https://leonardofaria.net/2012/12/31/configurando-o-sublime-text-2/">3 years ago I wrote&lt;/a> (in Portuguese) a post about my Sublime Text settings. Now, I updated my tips in an English post.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-free-video-course">1. Free video course&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you know nothing about Sublime, please watch &lt;a href="https://code.tutsplus.com/courses/perfect-workflow-in-sublime-text-2">these free videos&lt;/a> from tut+.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-package-control">2. Package Control&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>First of all, you should install Package Control to manage plugins. Actually, you can install packages just copying the package files to correct folder, however, Package Control is easier than copy &amp;amp; paste. Open Sublime Text console (View &amp;gt; Show Console or &lt;code>ctrl + `&lt;/code>) and paste the following line:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Useful apps that I use daily</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/09/17/useful-apps-that-i-use-daily/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 12:56:58 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/09/17/useful-apps-that-i-use-daily/</guid><description>&lt;p>I decided write a post describing some tools that I use in my MacBook to enhance my tasks.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="alfred">Alfred&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>How awesome is Alfred? It is totally awesome! Alfred is a great tool working as a shortcut to daily tasks. More than that, you can create customized workflows that improve even more your productivity. You must see:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.alfredforum.com/topic/3154-yet-another-window-layout-workflow/">Yet another layouter&lt;/a>: you can use keyworks like top left, top right to resize and move windows. This is really useful for people who use multiple displays&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.alfredforum.com/topic/1211-battery-view-summary-stats-about-your-laptop-battery/">Battery&lt;/a>: it is a workflow that shows relevant information about battery, such as charge cycles, health and serial number&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.alfredforum.com/forum/3-share-your-workflows/">Alfred Workflows Forum&lt;/a>: the community forum where people share their workflows&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.packal.org/">Packal&lt;/a>: an unofficial directory of workflows and themes. My currently theme is the &lt;a href="http://www.packal.org/theme/elegant-v4">Elegant v4&lt;/a>, but you can choose your favorite in &lt;a href="http://www.packal.org/theme-list?items_per_page=60">several options&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>A new place</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/09/11/a-new-place/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 19:04:24 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/09/11/a-new-place/</guid><description>I have just moved this week to Vancouver. I started my Web and Mobile App Design and Development post-degree in Langara.
Maybe I should write a blog talking about cultural differences between Brazil and Canada, like dozens of Brazilians but I think that those pages show limited or inaccurate point of views.
New times are coming! :)</description></item><item><title>Data looks better naked</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/08/31/data-looks-better-naked/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 17:29:46 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/08/31/data-looks-better-naked/</guid><description>&lt;p>Data is usually explained in tables or charts, but people sometimes commit mistakes when they add in them redundant or boring elements. A good table or chart is worth a thousand words and the following three gifs show how to improve your presentations. &lt;a href="https://darkhorseanalytics.com/blog/data-looks-better-naked/">Source&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/ClearOffPieChart.gif">&lt;img src="https://leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/ClearOffPieChart.gif" alt="Remove to improve - the pie chart edition">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>codestacker in Github</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/08/26/codestacker-in-github/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 19:26:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/08/26/codestacker-in-github/</guid><description>Some years ago, precisely on July/2008 I created codestacker. I know, there were several options to collect snippets, but I decided to code my own solution. More than that I have planned to develop a Textmate bundle and a Mac OS Widget (who cares?), however I did not code these functions.
In the latest days, I migrated all old data to a new app written in Rails 4.2 and hosted on Heroku.</description></item><item><title>One line webservers for everybody</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/08/16/one-line-webservers-for-everybody/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 13:38:47 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/08/16/one-line-webservers-for-everybody/</guid><description>Sometimes it is necessary to serve a folder with static resources (images, for example) as a web server. The probably most popular commands to perform these tasks are:
php -S localhost:9999 python -m SimpleHTTPServer 9999 The option that uses PHP built-in web server requires PHP 5.4+. The following gist provides several other ways to run a webserver locally.</description></item><item><title>Useful Chrome extensions to developers</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/07/20/useful-chrome-extensions-to-developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 09:24:03 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/07/20/useful-chrome-extensions-to-developers/</guid><description>&lt;p>First of all, you must see &lt;a href="https://umaar.com/dev-tips/">Dev Tips&lt;/a>: developer tips delivered daily in your email.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://umaar.com/dev-tips/17-quick-edit-element/">&lt;img src="https://umaar.com/assets/images/dev-tips/quick-edit-element.gif" alt="">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, these are some useful extensions that I&amp;rsquo;ve been using in Chrome to help me to develop webapps:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uptime monitoring tools</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/07/10/uptime-monitoring-tools/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 08:26:05 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/07/10/uptime-monitoring-tools/</guid><description>Sometimes people cann&amp;rsquo;t believe in their infrastructure. This can be easily understood because maintaining complex software integrates several pieces of information. Moreover, people sometimes hire bad IT solutions and as a result, shit accidents happen.
I have been using some tools to report me web server down time. Here we go:
monitor.us: it is a powerful tool that provides several features. I am currently using it to monitor a specific term in a specific page.</description></item><item><title>Writing for IELTS and TOEFL</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/06/10/writing-skills-for-ielts-and-toefl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 17:44:14 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/06/10/writing-skills-for-ielts-and-toefl/</guid><description>I took the TOEFL exam some weeks ago. This is one of most popular tests to prove English skills. It is considered by many people a tough exam because it requires not only English skills, but also time management skills.
The test takes 4 hours to be finished. The last part of the test is to write 2 texts in 50 minutes. In the first task, the student is supposed to summarise a text and a lecture, which lecture sometimes cast doubt in the passage.</description></item><item><title>Notice about future</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/05/31/notice-about-future/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 20:29:07 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2015/05/31/notice-about-future/</guid><description>I stopped writing in this blog for a while. I have been using this blog since 2005 and my absence is justified by live changes.
I am going to write my posts in English but texts in Portuguese could appear eventually. Sorry for eventual grammar mistakes ;)</description></item></channel></rss>