<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hugo on Leonardo Faria</title><link>http://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/categories/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in hugo on Leonardo Faria</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/categories/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3 privacy-focused open-source Google Analytics alternatives for your next project</title><link>http://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/2020/09/01/three-privacy-focused-open-source-google-analytics-alternatives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/2020/09/01/three-privacy-focused-open-source-google-analytics-alternatives/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a content creator, I like to know page analytics of my website. Overall, I am curious to learn how many people are reading my content, where they came from (referrer and countries) and what are the most popular pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>20 years ago, tools like &lt;a href="http://www.webalizer.org/">Webalizer&lt;/a> were all that we could count on. This tool parses the Apache logs and create static pages with the processed data. Another way to get page analytics would be inserting an image - often invisible - in your website. By using the request headers sent to the server, people could count visitors and get a little bit more information such as origin IP, browser, operational system. The technique is old but services like &lt;a href="https://statcounter.com/">statcounter&lt;/a> are still around providing this functionality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/webalizer.jpg" alt="Webalizer screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2005 Google launched Google Analytics after acquiring &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Urchin_(software)">Urchin&lt;/a>, a company which also analyzed server logs. Its presence has been growing since the early days and it is far from any competitor. There are a few reasons &lt;a href="https://plausible.io/blog/remove-google-analytics">why you should stop using Google Analytics on your website&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>It is owned by Google: Google uses Analytics in their benefit.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It affects site&amp;rsquo;s speed, by adding 45KB in page requests.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It is too invasive, collecting lots of personal data that you don&amp;rsquo;t need.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It is blocked by many plugins and browsers, creating inaccurate data.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>With all of this in mind, I want to share a few open-source alternatives I have been looking at in the last few months.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fathom">Fathom&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://usefathom.com/">Fathom&lt;/a> (&lt;a href="https://app.usefathom.com/share/sqqvo/chimp+essentials">demo&lt;/a>) is a light golang app to collect analytics. They have different paid plans, starting at $14/month and a lite version that you can install in your server or Heroku for free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/fathom.jpg" alt="Fathom screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lite version uses cookies and it gives you information about unique visitors, page views, average time on site, bounce rate, top pages and top referrers. Fathom stores data in SQLite, MySQL or Postgresql databases.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="umami">umami&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://umami.is/">umami&lt;/a> (&lt;a href="https://app.umami.is/share/ISgW2qz8/flightphp.com">demo&lt;/a>) is a solution created with Next.js. I did like how easy it is to deploy it - in my case, I am using Vercel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>umami shows the same data available in the lite version of Fathom &lt;em>plus&lt;/em> information about countries, browsers, operational system and device data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/umami.jpg" alt="Umami screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="plausible">Plausible&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I think I first heard about &lt;a href="https://plausible.io/">Plausible&lt;/a> (&lt;a href="https://plausible.io/plausible.io">demo&lt;/a>) in the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://changelog.com/podcast/396">De-Google-ing your website analytics&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; Changelog podcast. From a product perspective, it is nice to see a &lt;a href="https://plausible.io/roadmap">public roadmap&lt;/a> out in the wild so customers can learn what is coming next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Their plans start at $6/month and go up according to your page views - like Fathom. They have an &lt;em>alpha&lt;/em> self-hosted option (I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a chance to test it)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/plausible.jpg" alt="Plausible screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are alternatives out there and you don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about privacy or big corp looking at your users with these options. Their setup time is very similar among themselves and once you have it done, you can add multiple sites, as you do with Google Analytics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t have a favourite here. Feature-wise, umami gives all the basic information you may be curious about it for free and it is very easy to setup in services like Vercel or Netlify. Both Fathom and Plausible offer free trials so you can easily test their solutions before deciding it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Do you know another minimalist, open-source alternative to Google Analytics? Let me know in the comments.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bento theme released</title><link>http://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/2020/07/29/bento-theme-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/2020/07/29/bento-theme-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/2020/04/21/moving-to-hugo/">Earlier on April&lt;/a> I moved this website from Wordpress to Hugo. I like how Hugo is minimalist, fast and the fact I don&amp;rsquo;t need to maintain one more JavaScript codebase :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I created a theme for this website inspired by Casper (v1), Medium and many other minimalist journal templates. Bento was &lt;a href="https://themes.gohugo.io/bento/">just released&lt;/a> in the &lt;a href="https://themes.gohugo.io/">Hugo Themes website&lt;/a> and I decided to do here a show &amp;amp; tell about the work done.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="design">Design&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I have decided to use the OS default typography and lots of gray and blue colors. The color palette is the default TailwindCSS &lt;a href="https://tailwindcss.com/docs/customizing-colors/#default-color-palette">color palette&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tailwindcss">TailwindCSS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>TailwindCSS is my go-to option for CSS in personal projects. It is easy to use, customizable (if I have to) and I just don&amp;rsquo;t need to reinvent the wheel. I did write a few CSS code in the theme (ex: styles of the articles) but even for that I use TailwindCSS &lt;a href="https://tailwindcss.com/docs/extracting-components/#extracting-css-components-with-apply">&lt;code>@apply&lt;/code>&lt;/a> technique.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="little-big-details">Little big details&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the theme I used transitions for links colors, a gradient in the bottom of the page and last not least, a cool reading progress bar in the top of the page.&lt;/p>
&lt;video class="h-auto" controls autoplay="autoplay">
&lt;source src="http://leonardofaria.github.io/leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/page-scroll.mp4" type="video/mp4">
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>One of my favourite things in this layout is the backdrop-filter in the sticky header. The &lt;a href="https://web.dev/backdrop-filter/">&lt;code>backdrop-filter&lt;/code>&lt;/a> CSS property is very popular in iOS and I wanted to add this touch in the theme instead of having the usual opacity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I spend lots of my time on GitHub, I chose their color palette for code.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="performance">Performance&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I built Bento with Performance in mind. I wanted to deliver fast pages and no bloated CSS.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="turbolinks">Turbolinks&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>From &lt;a href="https://github.com/turbolinks/turbolinks">their README&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Turbolinks® makes navigating your web application faster. Get the performance benefits of a single-page application without the added complexity of a client-side JavaScript framework. Use HTML to render your views on the server side and link to pages as usual. When you follow a link, Turbolinks automatically fetches the page, swaps in its &lt;body>, and merges its &lt;code>&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/code>, all without incurring the cost of a full page load.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Turbolinks is well-known in the Rails community but it can also be used outside the framework. I saw it first at &lt;a href="https://devinschulz.com/">Devin Schulz&lt;/a> Hugo website and I decided to add it in my theme. The integration is painless: add the JS file from a CDN in your page and there is no step 2. Since I don&amp;rsquo;t have lots of JS interactions here, adding Turbolinks was very straightforward.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="postcss">PostCSS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>CSS libraries like Bootstrap and TailwindCSS are often critized for their weight. Offering modular styles has its tradeoff however packages like &lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@fullhuman/postcss-purgecss">postcss-purgecss&lt;/a> can avoid the big CSS files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The setup I used here came from the &lt;a href="https://github.com/budparr/hugopipes-tailwindcss">hugopipes-tailwindcss&lt;/a>, in case you are curious.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="future">Future&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I am quite happy with Bento right now but I may work in some features in the future, like adding search or subtle animations for images. Talking about images, adding neumorphism shadows would also be a nice touch.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>