<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hugo on Leonardo Faria</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/categories/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in hugo on Leonardo Faria</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 11:41:56 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leonardofaria.net/categories/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moving to Hugo</title><link>https://leonardofaria.net/2020/04/21/moving-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 11:41:56 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://leonardofaria.net/2020/04/21/moving-to-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the last few days, I worked to move this website to &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a>. I have been using WordPress for years (this domain turned 15 earlier this month) in a dozen projects however it was time to change. Decided to follow a minimalist setup with Hugo.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="about-the-stack">About the stack&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I decided to use Hugo here because I wanted something simple. KISS. I like Gatsby and Next.js however I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to choose a JavaScript solution. To achieve similar setup, I would have to add too many dependencies and they would become outdated quickly (rephasing &lt;a href="https://wesbos.com/new-wesbos-website/#Serverless-Functions">Wes Bos&lt;/a>). That&amp;rsquo;s being said, I need to mention that I am using JS to strip the extra classes from Tailwind CSS.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="about-the-design">About the design&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My previous site used a theme called &lt;a href="http://lacymorrow.com/casper/">Casper&lt;/a>, which is inspired in &lt;a href="https://ghost.org/">Ghost&amp;rsquo;s default theme&lt;/a>. I decided to build the theme from scratch inspired by Casper, Medium and many other minimalist blogs. I still have a feel things to fix/improve but designwise I am quite happy with the result.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I mentioned before, I used &lt;a href="https://tailwindcss.com/">Tailwind CSS&lt;/a> in this project. The utility-first approach definitely makes prototying faster. To avoid a bloated CSS file I am using a &lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@fullhuman/postcss-purgecss">purgecss package&lt;/a> to remove all the classes I am not using in the site. The final result is a 2.5KB CSS file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The previous WordPress had a good score in Lighthouse tests, and I was able to make it even better:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://leonardofaria.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/lighthouse.jpg" alt="Lighthouse results">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The theme is called &lt;a href="http://bento-hugo-theme.netlify.com/">Bento&lt;/a> and it is &lt;a href="https://github.com/leonardofaria/bento">open-source&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>